A Guide to the Eliza Selden Washington papers, 1825-1877
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Eliza Selden Washington papers 1825-1877
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 2004.19
136 items.
Washington, Eliza Selden
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 2004
Biographical/Historical Information
Eliza Selden Washington was the daughter of John Augustine Washington.
Scope and Content
Papers of Eliza Selden Washington (1848-1909), dating from June 1825 to February 1877. Chiefly, letters to and from Eliza Selden Washington and other family members in Virginia and West Virginia concerning family matters and several references to Mount Vernon and the Civil War. The collection contains some items of Eliza's father, John Augustine Washington, Jr. (1820-1861), including correspondence, a lock of his hair, and violets taken by him from Mount Vernon as he left for war in 1861. John Augustine Washington, Jr. was the grand-nephew of George Washington and the last private owner of Mount Vernon.
Arrangement
The papers have been inventoried but not arranged.
Index Terms
Persons:
Washington, Eliza Selden, 1848-1909 - correspondence; Washington, John Augustine, 1821-1861 - correspondence; Alexander, Charlotte - correspondence; Alexander, Judith B. - correspondence; Alexander, Minnie - correspondence; Alexander, W.F. - correspondence; Lloyd, John - correspondence; Lloyd, Rebecca - correspondence; Washington, Anna Maria - correspondence; Washington, Christian M. - correspondence; Washington, Eleanor Seldon - correspondence; Washington, George fl. 1860s - correspondence; Washington, Jane C. - correspondence; Washington, Jane Charlotte - correspondence; Washington, Louisa F. - correspondence; Washington, Richard Blackburn - correspondence
Geographical Names:
Mount Vernon (Va.: Estate); United States - History - Civil War, 1861-1865.
Contents List
- Rough inventory of Eliza Selden Washington papers
  - J.A. Washington to Richard B. Washington, 24 December 182[9] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - J.A. Washington to Thomas B. Washington, February 5, 1839
  - J.A. Washington to Thomas B. Washington, March 13, 1831
  - John A. Washington to Jane C. Washington, February 27, 1838
  - John A. Washington to Jane C. Washington, August 18, 1844
  - John A. Washington to Jane C. Washington, July 1, 1845
  - John A. Washington to Lily Washington, September 1, 1858
  - Violets from Mt. Vernon, 1861
  - Child's essay on Wampum
  - Hair from John Augustine Washington, his wife, Eliza Selden Washington, and Jane C. Washington
  - Newspaper article regarding Mrs. Eleanor Washington Howard
  - E[liza] Washington to Jane C. Washington, May 31, 1844 (Folder 2)
  - Maria Washington to Lily Washington, October 8, 1868
  - Maria Washington to Lily Washington, November 15, 1869
  - Maria Washington to Lily Washington, December 25, 1863
  - Maria Washington to Lily Washington, February 7, 1864
  - Maria Washington to Lily Washington, May 12, 1866
  - Letter to children, undated
  - Maria Washington to Lily Washington, November 18, no year
  - Note to Cousin Lily, undated (Folder 3)
  - Letter to Cousin Lily, undated
  - Note in child's hand, undated
  - Letter to "dearest girls", undated
  - W.F. Alexander to Lily, December 25, 1855
  - Judith Alexander to Eliza Selden Washington, undated
  - Wedding announcement, Robert W. Hunter and Eliza Selden Washington, 1895
  - Rebecca Lloyd to Lily, January 5, 1858
  - [Unknown] to Lily, undated
  - [Unknown] to George, July [year unknown] (Folder 4)
  - Writ of Ad Quad Dominium, December 28, 1790 and Tobacco invoice (on verso), May 8, 1791
  - Wilson Cary Selden to John Bagley, August 2, 1801
  - Monthly grade report for Walter Washington, Claymont Boarding School, March1869
  - Monthly grade report for Eliza S. Washington, Piedmont Institute, Charlottesville, VA, December -January, 1864
  - Monthly grade report for G. Washington, Shadwell School, December 1875
  - Judith B. Alexander to Eliza Selden Washington, November 20, 1863
  - Letter fragment (Folder 5)
  - [Aunt] to Maria, undated
  - Christian to Lily, undated
  - Note to Lily, undated
  - Christian to Eliza, October 13, 1866
  - Jean to Lily, undated
  - Eleanor to Lily, undated
  - Christian to Eliza, undated
  - Jean to Lily, undated (Folder 6)
  - [Unknown] to Lily, Charlestown, October 22, [year unknown]
  - Louisa to Lily, November 5, 1863
  - George to Lily, November 26, 1862
  - Eliza to Lily, June 19, 1862
  - Jean Washington to Lily, April 10, no year
  - Fragment from Eliza A. Selden
  - Phillipa Page to Mrs. J.A. Washington, August 10, 1860
  - Aunt Fannie to Rammie, September 8, 1863 (Folder 7)
  - Note, signed E
  - Unsigned letter, undated
  - Jane Charlotte to Lily, February10, [year]
  - L[ouisa] to Lilly, June 25, [year]
  - Other pieces too difficult to read
  - Note to Lily, initials, undated (Folder 8)
  - Nellie Washington to Lily, October 19, 1866
  - Lily
  - Eliza
  - Lily from her sister
  - Jean to Lily, May 31, 1867
  - J.L. to Lily, undated
  - Receipt, April 28, 1870
  - Louisa to her girls
  - Illegible
  - Fragment (Folder 9)
  - L[ouisa]À to Lily, undated (4 letters)
  - Richie to Lily, undated
  - Jean to Lila, June 27, [no year]
  - [Illegible] to Lily, undated
  - Aunt Christian À to Lily, undated
  - J.C. to Lily, undated
  - L[ouisa] to Lily, undated (Folder 10)
  - Christian to "My dear girls", undated
  - J.C. to [unknown], undated
  - J.C. to Lily, undated
  - Minnie to Lily, undated
  - Christian to Lily, undated
  - Fragments (2)
  - Fragment, Jean to Lily, undated
  - [Daughter] to Papa, undated (Folder 11)
  - Nell to Lila, January 1870
  - Aunt E.A.S. to Lily, January 3, 1867
  - Bridget to Biddy, June 25, 1868
  - E.A.S. to [Granddaughter], undated
  - Jean to Lily, April 16, 1867
  - Jean to Lily, March10, [year unknown]
  - Jean to Lily, April 7, 1867
  - Jean to "My darling little goose", September 29, 1866
  - Written from Piedmont to Lily, June 10 [no year]
  - Judith B. Alexander to Eliza, December 25, 1865 (Folder 12)
  - R.B. Washington to Eliza, undated
  - Jean to Lily, undated
  - Maria to Jean, May [illegible]
  - Rough draft, letter,Eliza S. Washington Hunter, Regent, Mount Vernon Chapter, D.A.R., to Mrs. Josephine Swann
  - Note
  - Note, J.C. to Lily, undated
  - Jean Washington to Lily, November 13, 1866
  - R.B. Washington and Christian Washington to Eliza, December 26, 1863
  - [Uncertain] to Lily, January 30, [no year] (Folder 13)
  - [Uncertain] to Lily, January 1, 1864
  - L[ouisa] to Lily, undated
  - J.S.T. to Son, undated
  - Christian to Lily, June 22, 1867
  - R.B. to Lily, December 16, 1866
  - Note from Jean, undated
  - Unknown to Liza (incomplete), July 26, [no year]
  - Jean to Lily, undated (Folder 14)
  - [Friend] to Lily, February14, 1870
  - [too difficult]
  - [Uncertain] to Lily, undated
  - Maria Washington to Lily, January 3, 1867
  - L[ouisa] to Lily, March6, [no year]
  - [Uncertain] to Lily, March26, [no year]
  - Rebecca Lloyd and Eliza Lloyd to Lily, May 20, 1864
  - Rebecca Lloyd to Lily, March8, 1871
  - Jeannie to Lily, July 8, 1868 (Folder 15)
  - Christian to Lily, November 30, 1866
  - [Uncertain, at Blakely] to Lily, December 4, 1866
  - Christian to Lily, June 5, 1867
  - Christian to Lily, January 16, 1864
  - Christian to Lily, October 26, 1868 À
  - Christian to Eliza, December 19, 1863
  - Jean to Lila, undated
  - L[ouisa] to Lily, March19, [no year] (Folder 16)
  - L[ouisa] to Lily, November 15, [no year]
  - John Lloyd to Lila, March6, 1871
  - [Uncertain] to Lily, undated
  - Christian to Eliza, June 23, 1867
  - Jean to [Lily], November 7, 1867
  - Jean to Lily, July 3, 1867
  - Christian to Maria, September 1866
  - J.B. Alexander to Mrs. J.C. Washington, November 14, 1844
  - W.F. Alexander to Nelly, November 30, 1854 (Folder 17)
  - [Cousin] to Leila Baker, June 7, 1825
  - [Uncertain] to Nelly, August 3, [no year]
  - W.F. Alexander to Nelly, December 13, 1858
  - [Illegible] to Nelly, February1, 1856
  - Rough draft of note, undated